<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>powertabeditor.desktop</id>
  
  <name>Power Tab Editor</name>
  <summary>View and edit guitar tablature</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      Power Tab Editor is an easy to use cross-platform guitar tablature editor and viewer.
      It is an open source, community-driven successor to the original Power Tab Editor 1.7.
      A variety of file formats are supported, including .pt2, .ptb, .gp3, .gp4, .gp5, .gpx, and .gp
    </p>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">powertabeditor.desktop</launchable>
  
  <categories>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
    <category>Music</category>
  </categories>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/issues</url>
  <url type="translate">https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/powertabeditor</url>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Main window</caption>
      <image>https://powertab.github.io/images/screenshot_linux.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <provides>
    <binary>powertabeditor</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="2.0.0-alpha16" date="2021-12-28">
      <url>https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/releases/tag/2.0.0-alpha16</url>
      <description>
        <p>New Features / Improvements</h3>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for tremolo bars (#8).</li>
          <li>.pt2 files are now 3-4x smaller in file size.</li>
          <li>The Windows installer has been revamped. It is recommended to first uninstall the existing version before upgrading.</li>
          <li>For Linux users, the application can now be easily installed as a Snap package (https://snapcraft.io/powertabeditor).</li>
          <li>The macOS installers are now signed and notarized. This resolves the Gatekeeper warnings when running for the first time.</li>
          <li>The application can now be translated into other languages</a>.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changes<p>
        <ul>
          <li>Removed dependency on boost::filesystem. Instead, std::filesystem (C++17) is now used. See the README for updated build instructions.</li>
          <li>Removed dependency on RapidJSON with nlohmann-json. See the README for updated build instructions.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed an issue where stopping MIDI playback while a `let ring` was active could incorrectly keep the `let ring` active when restarting playback from the beginning (#337).</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where the mixer's volume settings could be ignored when starting MIDI playback partway through the score (#335).</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where the score's title could be scaled incorrectly when printed (#338).</li>
          <li>Fixed potential crashes on exit when the tuning dictionary failed to load (#342).</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that could cause player changes to be incorrect created from .ptb files. This could lead to later issues with MIDI playback.</li>
          <li>Fixed issues where .ptb files containing multiple text items at the same position did not import correctly.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug in the score polisher that could multiple notes to end up at the same position. This could lead to later issues with editing and MIDI playback.</li>
          <li>Improvements for how the first barline in a system is rendered (#2).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
