<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>powertabeditor.desktop</id>
  
  <name>Power Tab Editor</name>
  <summary>View and edit guitar tablature</summary>
  <developer id="com.github.powertab">
    <name>Power Tab Developers</name>
  </developer>
  
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      Power Tab Editor is an easy to use cross-platform guitar tablature editor and viewer.
      It is an open source, community-driven successor to the original Power Tab Editor 1.7.
      A variety of file formats are supported, including .pt2, .ptb, .gp3, .gp4, .gp5, .gpx, and .gp
    </p>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">powertabeditor.desktop</launchable>
  
  <categories>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
    <category>Music</category>
  </categories>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/issues</url>
  <url type="translate">https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/powertabeditor</url>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Main window</caption>
      <image>https://powertab.github.io/images/screenshot_linux.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <provides>
    <binary>powertabeditor</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="2.0.22" date="2025-06-29">
      <url>https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/releases/tag/2.0.22</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated translations</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed issues with overriding the application's language on macOS via the system settings (#507)</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue which could cause a secondary language to be used for translations rather than the primary system language (#527, #528)</li>
          <li>Added missing German and Chinese (Simplified) translations which previously were not being packaged</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.21" date="2024-11-20">
      <url>https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/releases/tag/2.0.21</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The barline under the cursor can now be deleted without requiring it to be selected first</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed AppStream validation issues in `xdg/powertabeditor.metainfo.xml`</li>
          <li>Updated the MSVC redistributable for the Windows installer to be compatible with Visual Studio 2022</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug which could prevent barlines from being deleted (#496)</li>
          <li>Fixed errors with saving files in the Snap or Flatpak packages (#498)</li>
          <li>Fixed sizing issues in the playback widget on Windows (#495, #497)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.20" date="2024-11-03">
      <url>https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/releases/tag/2.0.20</url>
      <description>
        <p>New Features / Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Unsaved modified files can now be automatically backed at a regular interval, controlled via the Preferences dialog. The backup folder can be opened via the File menu (#392)</li>
          <li>The preferred MIDI output device is now tracked by name rather than by port number, which is more robust if e.g. a new device is plugged in</li>
          <li>Chord names can now use a custom label instead of the auto-generated chord name. This is primarily used for chords imported from Guitar Pro files (#442)</li>
          <li>When attempting to insert a note at the end of a system, a space is now automatically inserted to allow the note to be added (#439)</li>
          <li>Extended the view filter menu to support filtering by a specific player without requiring a filter to be explicitly created (#301)</li>
          <li>Copying and pasting selections which include barlines is now supported (#416)</li>
          <li>Improved the smoothness of MIDI pitch wheel events (bends, slides, etc), which now use the full 14-bit resolution instead of 7-bit</li>
          <li>Added Turkish translation (#406)</li>
          <li>Added Chinese (Simplified) translation (#476, #477, #482)</li>
          <li>Updated French translation (#406, #440)</li>
          <li>Updated German translation (#473, #474, #481, #482)</li>
          <li>Updated Russian translation (#407, #409, #437, #438)</li>
          <li>Updated Spanish translation (#445)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Chord diagrams now display the fret number of the top fret instead of the next fret after it (#408)</li>
          <li>Removed the 32-bit Windows installers</li>
          <li>A C++20 compiler is now required</li>
          <li>Updated the minimum required version of `RtMidi` to 4.0</li>
          <li>Updated the minimum required version of `boost` to 1.74</li>
          <li>Updated the minimum required version of `Qt` to 6.2</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a bug that caused some preferences such as custom shortcuts to not persist on macOS. Note that all other preferences (such as MIDI settings) are reset by this fix and will need to be manually changed to the desired values (#447)</li>
          <li>Fixed a frequent crash when the preference to play inserted notes while editing is enabled</li>
          <li>Fixed potential crashes when importing Guitar Pro files (#442, #444)</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where the scroll bar's range did not update when the visible height of the score shrank (#443)</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where the caret was rendered when printing or displaying a print preview (#441)</li>
          <li>Fixed issues where the top fret number of a chord diagram could be cut off in the chord name dialog (#408)</li>
          <li>Fixed a crash when an alternate ending was located on the last position of a system (#449)</li>
          <li>Fixed a crash during playback when a score contained a `Fine` symbol (#470)</li>
          <li>Fixed build errors with `minizip-ng` (#478)</li>
          <li>Fixed crashes due to menu items not being disabled correctly after switching tabs (#486)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0-alpha19" date="2022-10-17">
      <url>https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/releases/tag/2.0.0-alpha19</url>
      <description>
        <p>New Features / Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The spacing between systems can now be configured in the preferences (#239, #382)</li>
          <li>Added Japanese and Russian translations</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Rhythm slashes from `.ptb` files are now imported (as a regular staff for now, until full support for rhythm slashes is added) (#16, #389)</li>
          <li>Increased the upper limit for irregular grouping values (#376)</li>
          <li>The time signature dialog now enables the visibility checkbox by default (#356, #383)</li>
          <li>Improved rendering of slide outs from a note (#393)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed several potential errors when importing `.ptb` and Guitar Pro files.</li>
          <li>Fixed a potential crash when exporting to Guitar Pro (#379)</li>
          <li>Fixed issues where non-ASCII characters from `.ptb` files were not loaded correctly (#379)</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where some bars could be skipped when importing a Guitar Pro file with a small number of bars.</li>
          <li>Ties between notes in different systems are now supported by the Guitar Pro exporter.</li>
          <li>Fixed a regression from alpha 15 where the final barline in a system could not be edited.</li>
          <li>The snap package provides more helpful error messages when the MIDI device cannot be accessed (#386)</li>
          <li>Fixed a crash when editing multi-bar rests (#391)</li>
          <li>Fixed a potential crash when double-clicking to edit a bend (#390)</li>
          <li>Fixed a potential crash when using the Shift String Up / Down commands (#394)</li>
          <li>Fixed a potential crash when displaying imported `.ptb` files (#396)</li>
          <li>Fixed a MIDI playback issue where the pitch wheel could be incorrectly shifted when starting playback in the middle of the score (#395)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0-alpha18" date="2022-03-10">
      <url>https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/releases/tag/2.0.0-alpha18</url>
      <description>
        <p>New Features / Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for exporting to Guitar Pro 7 (`.gp`) files (#350)</li>
          <li>The Bulk Converter dialog can now export to MIDI files (and any export formats added in the future) instead of only `.pt2` files (#69)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The tuning dictionary in the user prefs folder (`tunings.json`) now only stores custom tunings instead of the entire tuning dictionary (#367)</li>
          <li>The user tuning dictionary is now combined with the default tuning dictionary when loaded, ensuring that updates to the default tunings take effect (#367)</li>
          <li>Reordered the default tuning dictionary so that "Down 1/2 Step", "Down 1 Step" etc tunings are next to the standard tuning (#367)</li>
          <li>Several changes to the `.pt2` JSON format to make it easier for other applications to parse (#368). Note that older releases will likely be unable to open newly-saved `.pt2` files</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed an error with importing `.gpx` or `.gp` files with artificial harmonics for which the harmonic type was set to `Pinch`</li>
          <li>Fixed a MIDI playback bug where let rings could ring forever in certain situations</li>
          <li>Added a b6 alteration for chord names (#370)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0-alpha17" date="2022-01-28">
      <url>https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/releases/tag/2.0.0-alpha17</url>
      <description>
        <p>New Features / Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for chord diagrams</li>
          <li>Chord diagrams are displayed at the top of the score</li>
          <li>Diagrams can be imported from v1.7 files and Guitar Pro 6 / 7 files</li>
          <li>The Chord Name dialog allows for quick selection from existing chord names in the score (chord text items, or chord diagrams)</li>
          <li>Use the Add Chord Diagram option in the text menu to add a new diagram</li>
          <li>Double-clicking a chord diagram will open a dialog to edit it, and selecting a chord diagram and pressing Delete will remove it</li>
          <li>Added MIDI playback support for bends that stretch over multiple notes</li>
          <li>Improvements for adjusting the score's zoom (#315, #340, #50)</li>
          <li>Added standard keyboard shortcuts for adjusting the zoom</li>
          <li>The last zoom level is saved in the settings and used when opening new scores</li>
          <li>Added a button in the playback widget to toggle the count-in option</li>
          <li>Added Spanish translation (#348)</li>
          <li>Added French translation (#355)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved the visibility of some colors in the dark score theme (#357)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed various playback issues with alternate endings (#306, #353, #354)</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where alternate endings could be drawn too far if there were multiple repeat end bars in a system</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where MIDI playback did not reset correctly if playback was interrupted during a pitch shift (e.g. bend or tremolo bar) (#361)</li>
          <li>When the Windows installer is run in silent mode, the option to launch the app after installing is now disabled</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where editing the first system could cause it to shift up and overlap with the score information or chord diagrams</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0-alpha16" date="2021-12-28">
      <url>https://github.com/powertab/powertabeditor/releases/tag/2.0.0-alpha16</url>
      <description>
        <p>New Features / Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for tremolo bars (#8).</li>
          <li>.pt2 files are now 3-4x smaller in file size.</li>
          <li>The Windows installer has been revamped. It is recommended to first uninstall the existing version before upgrading.</li>
          <li>For Linux users, the application can now be easily installed as a Snap package.</li>
          <li>The macOS installers are now signed and notarized. This resolves the Gatekeeper warnings when running for the first time.</li>
          <li>The application can now be translated into other languages.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Removed dependency on boost::filesystem. Instead, std::filesystem (C++17) is now used. See the README for updated build instructions.</li>
          <li>Removed dependency on RapidJSON with nlohmann-json. See the README for updated build instructions.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed an issue where stopping MIDI playback while a `let ring` was active could incorrectly keep the `let ring` active when restarting playback from the beginning (#337).</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where the mixer's volume settings could be ignored when starting MIDI playback partway through the score (#335).</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where the score's title could be scaled incorrectly when printed (#338).</li>
          <li>Fixed potential crashes on exit when the tuning dictionary failed to load (#342).</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that could cause player changes to be incorrect created from .ptb files. This could lead to later issues with MIDI playback.</li>
          <li>Fixed issues where .ptb files containing multiple text items at the same position did not import correctly.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug in the score polisher that could multiple notes to end up at the same position. This could lead to later issues with editing and MIDI playback.</li>
          <li>Improvements for how the first barline in a system is rendered (#2).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>guitar tab editor</keyword>
    <keyword>tablature viewer</keyword>
    <keyword>music notation software</keyword>
  </keywords>
</component>
